

#### **CONTACT ME AT**

- Remote Address Often
  Changes- best to contact me by
  email.
- alrobwilloliver@gmail.com
- www.alanoliver.dev
- in @alan-oliver-3a28aa118/

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- ESL Teaching
- International Communication
- Software Development
- Git
- Node JS
- Full Stack Development

#### AWARDS RECEIVED

- Outstanding Student Awards Mandarin Scholarship Spring
  and Summer Semesters (2018)
- Duke of Edinburgh Gold Award (2016)
- Year Group Best English Student (2016)

# **ALAN OLIVER**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER & ENGLISH TEACHER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a software developer with over 2 years experience, now working for a Blockchain company in Node JS and Golang building APIs on the backend. Prior, I have over 4 years professional experience teaching English at all ages, mostly adults.

In my spare time I enjoy learning about monetary policy, speaking Mandarin Chinese and travelling.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Junior Software Engineer

Cudo Ventures | Jan 2021 - present

- Develop new features on and maintain existing API..
- Implement tests for software to ensure reliablility.

#### Oral English Teacher

North Eastern Accounting and Finance University, Shandong, China | September 2019 - July 2021

- Develop curriculum for students in English, Finance and Tourism majors.
- Give lectures and lead classes.
- Examine students on their exam and performance.

## EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

# HuaZhong University of Science and Technology HSK 4 | Sep 2017 - June 2018

• Studied Mandarin listening, reading, speaking and writing at an intermediate level.

## University of Hull

BA Politics and History | Sep 2013 - June 2016

- 2:1
- Subjects included International Relations Theory, Political Philosophy, Counter Terrorism and Free Speech.
- Dissertation focussed on the Mongol military conquests and the political, social and economic impact in the Middle East regions of Persia.